你们好，美丽的人们，我非常祝贺你们通过了这一部分
Hello you beautiful people and I'm massive congratulations from me for making it through this section
与您的软件包管理器一起管理软件的课程。
of the course on managing software with your package manager.
我知道这很难，有很多新概念需要你去消化，但你做到了
Now I know it was a tough one with loads of new concepts for you to have to digest but you got there
无论如何，事实上，我们在课程的这一节中涵盖了太多的概念，所以我想选修
anyway and in fact we covered so many concepts in this section of the course that I wanted to take the
现在让我们快速回顾一下我们所报道的内容，并给您一些由衷的、当之无愧的赞扬。
time to have a quick recap of what we covered and to give you some wholehearted and well-deserved praise
走到这一步。
for making it this far.
所以恭喜你，做得很好。
So congratulations and well done.
我不知道互联网上还有其他课程或资源这么多地涉及到这些概念
I don't know of any other course or resource on the Internet that covers these concepts in that much
细节，所以你应该为自己消化它并一路走完而感到非常自豪。
detail so you should be very proud of yourself for digesting it and making it all the way through.
热烈祝贺你。
Massive Congratulations.
因此，让我们快速回顾一下我们在课程的这一部分中所涵盖的内容。
So let's have a quick recap of what we covered in this section of the course.
因此，首先我们开始讨论新项目和总体上的自由软件。
So first we started off by discussing the new project and free software in general.
你，他，你了解了理查德·斯托尔曼(Richard Stallman)在2005年启动的新项目的历史
And you he you learned about the history of the new project that was started by Richard Stallman in
1983年。
1983.
新项目开始的目的是创建一个基于给用户提供操作系统的操作目标
The new project started with the aim of operate of creating an operating system based upon giving users
自由控制软件的使用方式和功能。
freedom to control how the software was used and how it functions.
你学到了自由软件给你的四个自由，你也学到了一个先决条件
And you learned about the four freedoms that free software gives you and you learn that a prerequisite
对这些自由的要求是能够访问软件的源代码。
requirement for those freedoms is to have access to the source code of the software.
现在，因为这个软件是开放访问的，所以这种软件被称为开放源码软件。
Now because this software is openly accessible such software is called open source software.
好的。
OK.
现在，当我们转到一个网站时，然后我们转到网站，下载、修改和编译
Now when we headed over one then we headed over to the Web site and downloaded modified and compiled
我们自己版本的ls命令，所以无论何时，它都会说你好，你们这些漂亮的人
our very own version of the ls command so that it said hello there you beautiful people whenever it
已经跑了。
was run.
在此过程中，您需要使用make命令配置Good News C编译器。
And in that process you so I to configure the goodnews C-compiler using the make command.
因此我不得不编译代码并将其安装到您的系统上。
And so I had to compile code and install it on your system.
但这是一个相当乏味的过程，所以慕尼黑向您介绍了如何使用包管理器
But this was a rather tedious process and so Munich's introduced to you how to how to use package managers
和Buntu的软件存储库，许多发行版都有成千上万的软件
and software repositories of buntu and many of the distributions have thousands and thousands of software
可供您下载、试用和响应这些软件包的软件包存储在四个
packages available for you to download and try out and respond to these packages are stored in four
基于不同自由度和可靠性级别帮助保持软件分离的存储库
repositories that help keep software separated based upon the different freedoms and levels of reliability
它们提供给用户。
they give to the user.
所以主存储库是由Canonical维护的，Canonical是生产Buntu的公司，因此
So the main repository is maintained by canonical which is the company that makes a buntu and therefore
主存储库应该是您的第一个停靠点，宇宙存储库包含自由软件
the main repository should be your first port of call the universe repository contains free software
这是由社区维护的。
that is maintained by the community.
然后你有了受限的存储库，它包含了设备驱动程序的软件，然后你就有了
And then you've got the restricted repository which contains software for device drivers and then you've
获得了MultiVerse存储库，其中包含受法律和版权问题限制的软件。
got the multiverse repository which contains software restricted by legal and copy rights issues.
因此，我们随后前往Package的.buntu.com，浏览可用的软件包
So we then headed over to package's dot buntu dot com and browse through the packages that are available
敬我们。
to us.
我们看到有数以千计的套餐，每个套餐都可以有不同的套餐
We saw that there are thousands and thousands of packages that can be and they can each have different
依赖关系它们可以有不同的建议，它们可以有不同的版本号，因此
dependencies they can have different recommendations they can have different version numbers and so
然后您会意识到，尝试手动组织所有内容绝对是一场噩梦。
on and you realize that this would be an absolute nightmare to try and organize all manually.
这就是您了解Bantus包管理器的好处所在，该管理器将执行所有这些操作
And that's where you learned about the benefit of a Bantus package manager that will do all of that
对我们来说。
for us.
现在，几乎每个Linux发行版都有一个包管理器，但Kubuntu上的包管理器被称为apt
Now pretty much every Linux distribution has a package manager but the one on Kubuntu is called apt
代表高级包装工具。
which stands for Advanced packaging tool.
所以AAPT进行了高级包装谈话。
So AAPT for advance packaging talk.
现在，我们开始了解包管理器是如何工作的。
Now we then started to look at how the package manager works.
我们看到它将那些可用软件包的列表向下放入您系统的缓存中，您可以搜索
We saw that it down those lists of available packages into the cache on your system and you can search
此缓存用于与使用APT缓存搜索的搜索词相关的包，因此有关以下方面的更多信息
this cache for packages relevant to a search term using apt cache search and so more information about
使用APT缓存的给定软件包。
a given package using apt cache.
拥有缓存最重要的一点是确保它始终是最新的，并且您
And the most important thing about having a cache is making sure that it's always up to date and you
了解如何使用sudo apt get update更新缓存，以及有关包管理器的一件令人惊叹的事情
learn how to update the cache using sudo apt get update and one amazing thing about the package manager
是他们能够确保您系统上的所有软件都是一次性完全最新的。
is their ability to make sure that all the software on your system is completely up to date in one go.
现在，要执行此操作，您可以使用sudo apt get Upgrade。
Now to do this you use sudo apt get upgrade.
但是请记住，您应该始终确保缓存中的软件包列表首先是最新的
But remember that you should always make sure that the package lists in your cache up to date first
在将软件包升级到新版本号之前使用sudo apt get update。
using sudo apt get update before upgrading packages to the new version numbers.
使用sudo apt获得升级。
Using sudo apt get upgrade.
但是，为了使软件包保持最新，需要通过软件包进行安装
However in order to be able to keep a package up to date it needs to be installed through the package
管理器，而不是从源代码编译它。
manager and not compile it from source.
因此，萨度牢记这一点，并尽可能从软件存储库中安装软件包
So Sadu bear that in mind and try to install packages from the software repositories wherever possible
这实际上是我们谈到安装的下一个主题。
which is actually the next topic that we came onto installing.
您已经看到，可以使用sudo apt get install和软件包在系统上安装新的软件包
You saw that you can install new packages on your system using sudo apt get install and the packages
预编译好，然后就可以开始了。
come pre-compiled and ready to go.
您甚至不需要重新启动系统。
You don't even need to reboot your system.
好的，一旦您安装了它，我们安装了x11应用程序包，它就可以立即运行了，它为我们提供了
OK it's all ready to go as soon as you install it and we install the x 11 apps package which gave us
我们看到了很多其他的应用程序，比如X-Man，
the fun excised package to play around with and as we saw so many other applications such as X-Man which
是浏览手册页的图形化方式，但因为软件包是通过软件包安装的
is a graphical way of browsing the manual pages but because the package is installed via the package
管理器是预编译的，这意味着我们需要另一种方式来正确地查看源代码。
manager a pre-compiled that means we need another way to take a look at the source code right.
因此，接下来我们将讨论关于高度Buntu归档的结构化问题，以及如何配置我们的源DAAT列表
So then we discuss about highly buntu archives a structured and how to configure our sources daat list
文件来允许我们实际下载源代码。
file to allow us to actually download source code.
然后，我们下载了退出应用程序包的源代码，并查看了
We then downloaded the source code for the exit of an apps package and took a look at the code for the
接下来是我们看到的幕后程序，这段代码可以编译并安装在相同的
next ise program so we saw behind the scenes and this code can be compiled and installed in the same
作为代码，我们可以从网站下载，但请记住，这些代码是手动编译和安装的
way as the code we it from the web site but remember that code that's compiled and installed manually
失去了与包管理器保持最新的能力。
loses its loses its ability to be kept up to date with the package managers.
哦，顺便说一下，新网站上的所有内容也都在软件存储库中，所以您可以
Oh by the way everything that is on the new Web site is also in the software repositories so you can
向前看，只需使用存储库即可。
just use the repositories going forward.
最后，我们了解了如何使用包管理器卸载包来删除包。
And finally we saw how to uninstall packages using the package manager to remove a package.
最好的方法是sudo apt get perge，因为它会删除并移动符合以下条件的所有配置文件：
The best method is the sudo apt get Perge because that removes and moves any configuration files that
和包裹一起来的。
came with the package.
可能会留下来堵上你的硬盘。
Might just stay behind and clog up your hard drive.
因此sudo apt会被清除以删除软件包，而且当您安装软件包时，它通常带有一些依赖项
So sudo apt get purged to remove packages and when you install a package it often comes with some dependencies
这可能不再需要了。
that might no longer be needed.
卸载该软件包以便消除任何悬而未决的依赖项时，可以使用sudo apt get
When you uninstall that package so to get rid of any dangling dependencies you can use sudo apt get
自动删除。
auto remove.
因此，您还了解到，当安装软件包时，它不会死文件保存在本地计算机上。
So you also learned that when a package is installed it's not dead file is saved locally on the computer.
如果大量这样的文档死区堆积起来，它们真的会占用很大的空间。
And if a lot of these doc deadfalls build up they can really take up a lot of space.
因此，要移除所有这些黑暗的死角，您只需运行sudo apt get lean即可。
So to remove all of these dark deadfalls you simply run sudo apt get clean.
现在，您可能不想将其全部移除，而是只移除不再可访问的那些
Now you may not want to remove them all but instead just remove the ones that are no longer accessible
从储存库里。
from the repositories.
因此，要执行此操作，请运行sudo apt自动清理。
So to do that run sudo apt get auto clean.
好了，现在您对开放源码和自由软件的含义有了一个坚实的理解
OK now with that you now have a solid understanding of what open source and free software is all about
它是从哪里来的。
where it came from.
如何搜索如何安装它、如何管理它以及如何在您的新Linux计算机上卸载它。
How to search for how to install it how to manage it and how to uninstall it on your new Linux computer.
所以请记住，这些软件中的每一个都有自己的手册页，供您阅读和学习
So remember that each of these pieces of software comes with its own man page for you to read and learn
所以你现在完全自由了。
about the package as well so you've got complete freedom now.
我在这段视频的参考资料部分放了一张小抄，列出了每个命令和
I've put a cheat sheet in the resources section for this video that lays out each of the commands and
我们在本节中介绍的系统上的有用文件和文件夹，因此我们可以在以下情况下参考这些文件和文件夹
useful files and folders on the system that we've covered in this section so we can refer to that when
你在处理包裹。
you're working with packages.
如果你需要一点补习，但老实说，你在这一节已经走到这一步了，因为
If you ever need a bit of a refresher but in all honesty you have come so far in this section because
我为你感到难以置信的骄傲。
I am so unbelievably proud of you.
有一个庞大的软件世界等着你去探索，如果你能想到这一点，那就是
There is a whole massive world of software out there for you to explore and if you can think of it it's
可能在储存库中，所以去找一个在它前面的探索者。
probably in the repository so go and have an explore one ahead of it.
要在.com网站上搜索并查看和安装一些内容并尝试使用的软件包
Packages that are to dot com and have a search around and see and install some stuff and try it out
现在。
now.
不幸的是，所有美好的事情都必须结束，现在是我们需要结束
Unfortunately all good things must come to an end and the time has come that we need to wrap up the
当然可以。
course.
所以说再见吧，我会在下一个视频中见到你。
So to say goodbye I'll see you in the next video.